<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Application Software">
  <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID003">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Protection Profile for Application Software</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>.6</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2014-05-08</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>NIAP-whoknows</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>.01 Revision 0</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>application; software</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>v .1</version>
      <date>2013-01-08</date>
      <subject>Initial draft commit</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>v .6</version>
      <date>2013-03-14</date>
      <subject>Attractive presentation achieved</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <!-- TO DO: Distinguish citations from cross-references. Mark up each appropriately. 
                        Pick an attribute other than id to refer to the linked element. Transform 
                        them more intelligently. Better yet, use standard markup with tool support. -->
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">The scope of this Protection
    Profile (PP) is to describe the functionality of application software in
    terms of 
    <cite linkend="bibCC" />and to define functional and assurance requirements
    for such software. In recent years, software attacks have shifted from
    targeting operating systems to targeting applications. This has been the
    natural response to improvements in operating system security and
    development processes. As a result, it is paramount that the security of
    applications be improved to reduce the risk to client systems and
    enterprise networks.</section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary">The following sections provide both
    Common Criteria and technology terms used in this Protection Profile. 
    <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms" id="ccterms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
          <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
          <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security Evaluation</description>
        </entry>
          <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
          <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category of TOEs that meet specific customer needs.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
          <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific TOE.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
          <description>The product under evaluation. In this case, application software.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
          <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a TOE satisfies the SFRs in a ST.</description>
        </entry>
          <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
          <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the TOE.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
          <description>A requirement to assure the security of the TOE.</description>
        </entry>
      </glossary>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="Technology Terms" id="techterms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Address Space Layout Randomization">ASLR</abbr></term>
          <description>An anti-exploitation feature which loads memory mappings into unpredictable locations. ASLR makes it more difficult for an attacker to redirect control to code that they have introduced into the address space of an application process.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Application">app</abbr></term>
          <description>Software that runs on an operating system and performs tasks on behalf of the user or owner of the platform.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Application Programming Interface">API</abbr></term>
          <description>A specification of routines, data structures, object classes, and variables that allows an application to make use of services provided by another software component, such as a library. APIs are often provided for a set of libraries included with the operating system.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Credential</term>
          <description>Data that establishes the identity of a user, e.g. a cryptographic key or password</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Data Execution Prevention">DEP</abbr></term>
          <description>An anti-exploitation feature of modern operating systems executing on modern computer hardware, which enforces a non-execute permission on pages of memory. DEP prevents pages of memory from containing both data and instructions, which makes it more difficult for an attacker to introduce and execute code.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Developer</term>
          <description>An entity that writes application software. For the purposes of this document, vendors and developers are the same.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Device Owner/Machine Owner</term>
          <description>Entity that purchased and maintains ownership of a mobile device or computer.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Information Owner</term>
          <description>Entity whose information is stored and/or processed on a device or computer; can be an application-specific provider, a digital provider, or an enterprise that allows access to resources from mobile devices or remote computers.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term><abbr title="Operating System">OS</abbr></term>
          <description>Software that manages platform resources and provides services for applications.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Platform</term>
          <description>The physical or virtual environment in which software runs. From an operating system's perspective, the platform is the physical or virtual hardware. From an application's perspective, the platform is the operating system and the operating system's platform.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Stack Cookie</term>
          <description>An anti-exploitation feature that places a value on the stack at the start of a function call, and checks that the value is the same at the end of the function call. This is also refered to as Stack Guard, or Stack Canaries.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>Vendor</term>
          <description>An entity that sells application software. For purposes of this document, vendors and developers are the same. Vendors are responsible for maintaining and updating application software.</description>
        </entry>
      </glossary>
    </subsection></section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">The
    requirements in this document apply to all application software that runs
    on any operating system regardless of the function of the application,
    identity of the operating system, or composition of the underlying hardware
    platform. This includes mobile applications ("apps") as well as application
    software on desktop or server platforms. Some application types are covered
    by more specific PPs which may be expressed as Extended Packages of this
    PP. Such applications are subject to the requirements of both this PP and
    the PP that addresses their special functionality. For example, web
    browsers are subject to the requirements in this PP and the Protection
    Profile for Web Browsers. 
    <subsection title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary">An application is defined
    as software that runs on an operating system and performs tasks on behalf
    of the user or owner of the system. As distinguished from applications,
    operating system software manages hardware resources and provides a runtime
    environment for applications. Applications that come bundled with an
    operating system (such as web browsers, email clients and media players)
    fall within the scope of these requirements. Naturally, third-party
    software such as <abbr title="Portable Document Format">PDF</abbr> readers and downloadable smartphone apps is also in
    scope. Systems software that is delivered and installed with an application
    (such as kernel drivers) is considered part of the application for purposes
    of this document. <abbr title="Basic Input/Output System">BIOS</abbr> and other firmware, the operating system kernel, and
    other systems software (and drivers) that are included with the computing
    platform are outside the scope of this document. 
    <figure entity="images/appdiagram.png"
    title="Figure 1: Protection Profile Overview"
    id="generictoedesign" /></subsection></section>
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">Requirements in this Protection
    Profile are designed to address the security problem in the following use
    cases. These use cases are intentionally very broad, as many specific use
    cases exist for application software. Many applications may be used in
    combinations of these broad use cases as well. 
    <usecases>
      <usecase title="Content Creation" id="contentcreation">
        <description>The application allows a user to create or edits documents
        or other content, saving them to either local or remote
        storage.</description>
      </usecase>
      <usecase title="Content Consumption" id="contentconsumption">
        <description>The application allows a user to consume content,
        retrieving it from either local or remote storage.</description>
      </usecase>
      <usecase title="Communication" id="interactivecomms">
        <description>The application allows a user to communicate interactively
        or non-interactively with other users over a communications
        channel.</description>
      </usecase>
    </usecases></section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="ccl">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description>The PP requires strict conformance of any PPs/STs to this
        PP.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This PP is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (extended) of Common Criteria
        Version 3.1, Revision 4. 
        <cite linkend="bibCC" />.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="PP Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any other Protection
        Profile.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="Package Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any
        packages.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Problem Definition" id="spd">The security problem is
  described in terms of the threats that the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> is expected to address,
  assumptions about the operational environment, and any organizational
  security policies that the TOE is expected to enforce. 
  <section title="Threats" id="threats">
    <threats>
      <threat id="T.NETWORK_ATTACK">
        <description>An attacker is positioned on a communications channel or
        elsewhere on the network infrastructure. Attackers may engage in
        communications with the application software or alter communications
        between the application software and other endpoints in order to
        compromise it.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_COMMS">
          <rationale>The threat T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP is countered by
          O.PROTECTED_COMMS as this provides for integrity of transmitted
          data.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        <objective-refer ref="O.INTEGRITY">
          <rationale>The threat T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP is countered by O.INTEGRITY
          as this provides for integrity of software that is installed onto the
          system from the network.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </threat>
      <threat id="T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP">
        <description>An attacker is positioned on a communications channel or
        elsewhere on the network infrastructure. Attackers may monitor and gain
        access to data exchanged between the application and other
        endpoints.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_COMMS">
          <rationale>The threat T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP is countered by
          O.PROTECTED_COMMS as this provides for confidentiality of transmitted
          data.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        <objective-refer ref="O.QUALITY">
          <rationale>The objective O.QUALITY ensures use of mechanisms that
          provide strong protection against network-based attack.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </threat>
      <threat id="T.LOCAL_ATTACK">
        <description>An attacker can act through unprivileged software on the
        same computing platform on which the application executes. Attackers
        may provide maliciously formatted input to the application in the form
        of files or other local communications.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="O.QUALITY">
          <rationale>The objective O.QUALITY protects against the use of
          mechanisms that leave the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> open to attacks.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </threat>
      <threat id="T.PHYSICAL_ACCESS">
        <description>An attacker may try to access sensitive data at
        rest.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_STORAGE">
          <rationale>The objective O.PROTECTED_STORAGE protects against
          attempts to access physical storage used by the <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </threat>
    </threats>
  </section>
  <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
    <assumptions>
      <assumption id="A.PLATFORM">
        <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE" /> relies upon a trustworthy computing platform for
        its execution. This includes the underlying operating system and the
        runtime environment it provides to the TOE.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="OE.PLATFORM">
          <rationale>The assumption A.PLATFORM is covered by security
          objectives OE.PLATFORM as directly follows.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </assumption>
      <assumption id="A.PROPER_USER">
        <description>The user of the application software is not willfully
        negligent or hostile, and uses the software within compliance of a
        reasonable enterprise security policy.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="OE.PROPER_USER">
          <rationale>The assumption A.PROPER_USER is covered by objective
          OE.PROPER_USER as directly follows</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </assumption>
      <assumption id="A.PROPER_ADMIN">
        <description>The administrator of the application software is not
        careless, willfully negligent or hostile, and administers the software
        within compliance of a reasonable enterprise security
        policy.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="OE.PROPER_ADMIN">
          <rationale>The assumption A.PROPER_ADMIN is covered by objective
          OE.PROPER_ADMIN as directly follows</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </assumption>
    </assumptions>
  </section>
  <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="OSPs">
    <OSPs>
      <OSP id="P.ENTERPRISE">
        <description>The configuration of the application software must adhere
        to the enterprise security policy.</description>
        <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
          <rationale>The organizational security policy P.ENTERPRISE is
          enforced through the the objective O.MANAGEMENT as this objective
          represents how the enterprise asserts management over the
          <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
      </OSP>
    </OSPs>
  </section></chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE"
    id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.INTEGRITY">
          <description>To maintain their own integrity, conformant <abbr linkend="TOE" />s ensure
          the integrity of their installation and update packages, and also
          leverage execution environment-based mitigations. Software is seldom
          if ever shipped without errors, and the ability to deploy patches and
          updates to fielded software with integrity is critical to enterprise
          network security. Processor manufacturers, compiler developers, and
          operating system vendors have developed execution environment-based
          mitigations that increase the cost to attackers by adding complexity
          to the task of compromising systems. Application software can often
          take advantage of these mechanisms by using <abbr linkend="API" />s provided by the
          operating system or by enabling the mechanism through compiler or
          linker options.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fdp_dec_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fpt_aex_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fpt_tud_ext.1" />
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.QUALITY">
          <description>To ensure quality of implementation, conformant <abbr linkend="TOE" />s
          leverage services and <abbr linkend="API" />s provided by the operating system rather
          than implementing their own versions of these services and APIs. This
          is especially important for cryptographic services and other complex
          operations such as file and media parsing. Quality of implementation
          includes maintaining compatibility with future operating system
          versions and updates by using only documented and supported
          APIs.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fmt_mec_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fpt_api_ext.1" />
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.MANAGEMENT">
          <description>To facilitate management by users and the enterprise,
          conformant <abbr linkend="TOE" />s provide consistent and supported interfaces for their
          security-relevant configuration and maintenance. This includes the
          deployment of applications and application updates through the use of
          platform-supported deployment mechanisms and formats, as well as the
          use of platform-supported mechanisms for storing and setting
          configuration options.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fmt_cfg_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fmt_smf.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fpt_idv_ext.1" />
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PROTECTED_STORAGE">
          <description>To address the issue of loss of confidentiality of user
          data in the event of loss of physical control of the storage medium,
          conformant <abbr linkend="TOE" />s provide data-at-rest protection. This involves
          encrypting data and keys stored by the TOE in order to prevent
          unauthorized access to this encrypted data.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fdp_dar_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fcs_rbg_ext.1" />
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PROTECTED_COMMS">
          <description>To address network eavesdropping and network attack
          threats, conformant <abbr linkend="TOE" />s will provide a trusted communication path
          for sensitive data. Sensitive data includes cryptographic keys,
          passwords, and any other data specific to the application that should
          not be exposed outside of the application.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_rbg_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fcs_tls_ext.1" />
          <component-refer ref="fpr_ano_ext.1" />
          <!-- this may call for a separate protected_identity objective -->
          <component-refer ref="ftp_dit_ext.1" />
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment"
    id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment">The following security objectives
    for the operational environment assist the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> in correctly providing its
    security functionality. These track with the assumptions about the
    environment. 
    <SOEs>
      <SOE id="OE.PLATFORM">
        <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE" /> relies upon a trustworthy computing platform for
        its execution. This includes the underlying operating system and the
        runtime environment it provides to the TOE.</description>
      </SOE>
      <SOE id="OE.PROPER_USER">
        <description>The user of the application software is not willfully
        negligent or hostile, and uses the software within compliance of a
        reasonable enterprise security policy.</description>
      </SOE>
      <SOE id="OE.PROPER_ADMIN">
        <description>The administrator of the application software is not
        careless, willfully negligent or hostile, and administers the software
        within compliance of a reasonable enterprise security
        policy.</description>
      </SOE>
    </SOEs></section>
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR">This section
    describes how the assumptions, threats, and organizational security
    policies map to the security objectives. 
    <InsertSPDCorrespondence /></section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the
  security requirements which have to be fulfilled by the <abbr linkend="TOE" />. Those
  requirements comprise functional components from Part 2 and assurance
  components from Part 3 of 
  <cite linkend="bibCC" />. The following notations are used: 
  <ul>
    <li>
    <b>Refinement</b> operation (denoted by 
    <b>bold text</b>): is used to add details to a requirement, and thus
    further restricts a requirement.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Selection</b> (denoted by 
    <u>underlined text</u>): is used to select one or more options provided by
    the [CC] in stating a requirement.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by 
    <i>italicised text</i>): is used to assign a specific value to an
    unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the value
    in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses
    (e.g. "(1)")</li>
  </ul>
  <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFRs">The Security
  Functional Requirements included in this section are derived from Part 2 of
  the Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version
  3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional components. 
  <subsection title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="fdp">
    <component id="fdp_dec_ext.1" name="Access to Platform Resources">
      <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must provide user awareness <selectables atleastone="yes">
          <selectable>at install time</selectable>
          <selectable>at runtime</selectable>
          <selectable>in documentation</selectable>
        </selectables>, of any access to
        hardware resources that could provide access to sensitive information,
        such as camera, <abbr title="Wireless Local Area Network">WiFi</abbr>, Ethernet, <abbr title="Global Positioning System">GPS</abbr>, <abbr title="Near-Field Communication">NFC</abbr>, <abbr title="Universal Serial Bus">USB</abbr>, or Bluetooth.</title>
        
        <note role="application">Explicitly seeking user acknoweldgement for such
        access is one means of providing user awareness, but acknoweldgement is not a requirement for awareness.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install the application and inspect its
        user documentation, and determine that the user is informed of any need
        to access hardware resources which provide access to sensitive
        information. The method of doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall install the
        application and run it for the first time. The evaluator shall verify
        that the application displays all platform resources it would like to
        access. Note: If the user goes to: App permissions – Settings →
        Security and Privacy → Application Permissions → Select application in
        question, it will list which platform resource are approved/denied and
        can be changed.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall install the
        application and verify that the application displays the platform
        resources it would like to access. Note: Users must accept all
        requested permissions upon installation and cannot choose individual
        permissions to allow or deny.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">For Windows Store Apps the evaluator
        shall check the AppManifest.xml file for a list of required
        hardware capabilities. The evaluator shall verify that the user is made aware 
        of the required hardware when the application is first executed after being installed.
        For Windows Desktop Application the evaluator shall verify that either the application
        or the documentation provide the user with with a list of the required hardware 
        resources.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall install and run the
        application. The evaluator shall attempt to exercise Location Services
        functionality and verify that the application prompts the user for
        permission.</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application must provide user awareness <selectables atleastone="yes">
          <selectable>at install time</selectable>
          <selectable>at runtime</selectable>
          <selectable>in documentation</selectable>
        </selectables>, of any access to
        sensitive information repositories, such as address book, calendar, or
        caller lists.</title>
        <note role="application">While the application is responsible for requesting 
        access to sensitive information repositories, it is the operating system's responsibility
        to enforce whether or not the application can actually access those repositories.
        </note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install the application and inspect its
        user documentation, and determine that the user is informed of any need
        to access sensitive information which provide access to sensitive
        information repositories. The method of doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall install the
        application and run it for the first time. The evaluator shall verify
        that the application displays all platform resources it would like to
        access.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall install the
        application and verify that the application displays the permissions
        used to access sensitive information repositories.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">For Windows Store Apps the evaluator
        shall check the AppManifest.xml file for a list of required
        capabilities. The evaluator shall verify that the user is made aware 
        of the required information repositories when the application is first executed after being installed.
        For Windows Desktop Application the evaluator shall verify that either the application
        or the documentation provide the user with with a list of the required information repositories.
        </subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall install and run the
        application. The evaluator shall attempt to exercise functionality in
        the application that would cause it to access sensitive information
        repositories. The evaluator shall verify that the application prompts
        the user for permission.</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.3">
        <title>The application must not seek permission from the user to access
        resources which it does not require.</title>
        <note role="application">While the application is responsible for
        requesting access to a device, it is the operating system's
        responsibility to enforce whether or not the application can actually
        use the device.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall compare the list of resources required
        by the application with the list of resources indicated by the
        application itself. The method of doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The first time the application is
        started it displays all platform resources it would like to access.
        They can individually be approved or denied. Also if the user goes to:
        App permissions – Settings → Security and Privacy → Application
        Permissions → Select application in question, it will list which
        platform resource are approved/denied and can be
        changed.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall install the 
          application and confirm that it does not request more permissions than
          are necessary for the application to perform its described function. If 
          provided the evaluator shall look at the AndroidManifest.xml file to 
          confirm that the application does not request more permissions than are necessary.
        </subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">For Windows Store Apps the evaluator
        shall check the AppManifest.xml file for a list of required
        capabilities. The evaluator shall run the application and verify that
        the application only uses the capabilities listed in the
        AppManifest.xml file. For Win32 Desktop Application the developer must
        provide a written list of capabilities needed by the application. The
        evaluator shall run the desktop application and verify that the
        application only uses capabilities declared by the
        developer.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">TBD</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fdp_dar_ext.1" name="Storage Of Sensitive Application Data">
      <f-element id="fdp_dar_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must leverage platform-provided functionality
        for the encryption of sensitive data when it is stored in non-volatile
        memory.</title>
        <!-- this language is intentionally different from the MDPP's FDP_DAR -->
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall run the application and store
        potentially sensitive data. The evaluator shall then inspect the
        filesystem to determine where data has been written, and note whether
        it is encrypted. The evaluator shall also use static analysis to
        determine whether the platform-provided functionality for protecting
        sensitive data is leveraged. The method of doing so varies per
        platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall determine
        whether the application properly uses the Content Protection
        <abbr linkend="API" />.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall verify that the
        application uses the Android 
        <code>KeyStore</code>, 
        <code>SecretKeyFactory</code> and 
        <code>Cipher</code> classes to encrypt sensitive data.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall determine and
        verify that Windows Applications use the <abbr title="Data Protection API">DPAPI</abbr> to
        store and retrieve senstive information. Windows Store Apps for desktop
        or mobile shall utilize the DPAPI via the ProtectedData
        class.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall determine whether the
        application leverages the <abbr title="Data Protection API">DPAPI</abbr>.</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
  </subsection>
  <subsection title="Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt">
    <component id="fmt_mec_ext.1" name="Supported Configuration Mechanism">
      <f-element id="fmt_mec_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must use the mechanisms recommended by the
        operating system vendor for storing and setting TSF related configuration
        options.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator must identify the application's configuration
        data (e.g. settings) and determine whether it is stored and set using
        the mechanisms supported by the platform. The method of doing so varies
        per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall verify when the
        application is installed that all files included in the BAR are stored
        in the app folder of the Application working directory.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall determine and
        verify that the application stores all settings on internal storage.
        The application should make use of the 
        <code>SharedPreferences</code>and/or 
        <code>PreferenceActivity</code>classes for storing configuration
        data.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall determine and
        verify that Windows Store App applications use either the
        Windows.UI.ApplicationSettings namespace or the IsolatedStorageSettings
        namespace for storing application specific settings. Classic Desktop
        application shall use the Windows Registry or a structured file in the
        users profile. Locations used to store application settings must not be
        used for storing executable content.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall verify the application
        uses the defaults system</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fmt_mec_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application must use the mechanisms recommended by the
        operating system vendor for storing application data.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator must identify the application's source of data
        input and output and ensure it is stored in a location supported by the
        platform. The method of doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall verify when the
        application is installed that all files included in the BAR are stored
        in the app folder of the Application working directory.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall verify the
        following: 
        <ul>
          <li>The application stores all sensitive data on internal storage
          using either 
          <code>Context.MODE_PRIVATE</code> or 
          <code>SharedPreferences</code></li>
          <li>All keys shall be stored within a keystore using Android's 
          <code>KeyStore</code> class</li>
          <li>Files that are to be accessible by the user or other applications
          should be stored in an appropriate folder on external storage. The
          application should also be requesting the 
          <code>WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE</code> permission within the 
          <code>AndroidManifest.xml</code> file.</li>
        </ul></subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall determine and
        verify that Windows Store App applications use the IsolatedStorage
        namespace for storing application data. The evaluator shall determine
        and verify that classic Desktop application use a structed file in the
        users profile or the ProgramData directory, but not the applications
        executable directory. Locations used to store application data must not
        be used for storing executable content.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall verify the application
        uses the defaults system</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fmt_cfg_ext.1" name="Secure by Default Configuration">
      <f-element id="fmt_cfg_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must be configured by default to not use any
        default credentials.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install and run the application and
        inspect its documentation. If the application uses any credentials such
        as passwords or private keys, these must not be pre-programmed and the
        user must instead be prompted to provide the credential.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fmt_cfg_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application must be configured by default to not transmit
        any credentials in the clear.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install and run the application and
        inspect its documentation. The evaluator shall determine if the
        application uses any credentials such as passwords or private keys. The
        evaluator must sniff network traffic between the platform and any
        remote systems, and determine that these credentials are not
        transmitted in the clear.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fmt_cfg_ext.1.3">
        <title>The application must be configured by default to have file
        permissions which protect it from unprivileged processes.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install and run the application. The
        evaluator shall inspect the filesystem of the platform for any files
        created by the application and ensure that their permissions are
        adequate to protect them from unprivileged processes. The method of
        doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">TBD</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall verify using 
        <code>ls -l</code> that files writen to disk during installation have
        the correct file permissions.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall run the
        SysInternals tools, Process Monitor and Access Check, for Classis
        Desktop applications to verify that files writen to disk during an
        applications installation have the correct file permissions. Windows
        Store Apps will pass this by default because of the AppContainer
        sandbox.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">TBD</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fmt_cfg_ext.1.4">
        <title>The application must be configured by default to not transmit
        any personally-identifiable information (PII).</title>
        <note role="application">PII is concerned with user identity and does
        not include crashdumps or other information about system state.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install and run the application and
        inspect its documentation. The evaluator shall survey the list of
        settings for the application. If any setting controls the transmission
        of PII, it must be disabled by default.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fmt_smf.1" name="Specification of Management Functions">
      <f-element id="fmt_smf.1.1">
        <title>The <abbr linkend="TSF" /> shall be capable of performing the following management
        functions: 
        <ol>
          <li>enable/disable transmission of any system identity
          information</li>
          <li>enable/disable transmission of any user identity information</li>
          <li>enable/disable transmission of any application state (e.g.
          crashdump) information</li>
          <li>enable/disable automatic software update functionality</li>
        </ol></title>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <!-- <component id="fmt_not.1" name="Notification of Update"> 
                                        <f-element id="fmt_not.1.1">If the update process is initiated by an application, 
                                        then the application should report to the user the last time it checked for 
                                        available updates. </f-element> </component> -->
  </subsection>
  <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
    <component id="fcs_rbg_ext.1" name="Random Bit Generation">
      <f-element id="fcs_rbg_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must use random bit generation services provided
        by the platform.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall inspect the application and its
        developer documentation to determine if the application needs random
        bit generation services. If so, the evaluator shall determine how the
        application acquires random bits and ensure that these are acquired
        properly from the platform. This varies on a per-platform basis: 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The evaluator shall use static
        analysis to verify /dev/random or /dev/urandom is used.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall use static
        analysis to verify /dev/random or /dev/urandom is used.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall use static
        analysis to verify that the CryptGenRandom <abbr linkend="API" /> is used for classic
        desktop applications. The evaluator shall use static analysis to verify
        that the System.Random API is used for Windows Store
        Applications.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall use static analysis to
        verify /dev/random is used.</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
  <component id="fcs_tls_ext.1" name="TLS Implementation">
      <f-element id="fcs_tls_ext.1.1" status="sel-based">
		<selection-depends req="ftp_dit_ext.1.1"/>
        <title>The application shall implement one or more of the following
        <abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</abbr> protocols 
        <selectables linebreak="yes">
          <selectable>TLS 1.0 (RFC 2246)</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS 1.1 (RFC 4346)</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246)</selectable>
        </selectables>supporting the following ciphersuites: 
        <p />Mandatory Ciphersuites: TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA and 
        <p />Optional Ciphersuites: 
        <selectables linebreak="yes">
          <selectable>None</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA384</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA</selectable>
          <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA</selectable>
        </selectables>.</title>
        <note role="application">The ciphersuites to be tested in the evaluated
        configuration are limited by this requirement. The ST author should
        select the optional ciphersuites that are supported; if there are no
        ciphersuites supported other than the mandatory suites, then None
        should be selected. It is necessary to limit the ciphersuites that can
        be used in an evaluated configuration administratively on the server in
        the test environment. The Suite B algorithms listed above (RFC 6460)
        are the preferred algorithms for implementation.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall check the description of the
        implementation of this protocol in the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> to ensure that the
        ciphersuites supported are specified. The evaluator shall check the TSS
        to ensure that the ciphersuites specified include those listed for this
        component. The evaluator shall also check the operational guidance to
        ensure that it contains instructions on configuring the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> so that TLS
        conforms to the description in the TSS. The evaluator shall check that
        the AGD guidance contains instructions for the administrator to
        configure the list of Certificate Authorities that are allowed to sign
        certificates or to configure the FQDN of the authentication server
        certificate that will be accepted by the TOE in the EAP-TLS exchange.
        Additional tests may be added in the future to test compliance with RFC
        5246. The evaluator shall also perform the following tests: 
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall establish a TLS connection using each of
          the ciphersuites specified by the requirement. This connection may be
          established as part of the establishment of a higher-level protocol,
          e.g., as part of an EAP session. It is sufficient to observe the
          successful negotiation of a ciphersuite to satisfy the intent of the
          test; it is not necessary to examine the characteristics of the
          encrypted traffic in an attempt to discern the ciphersuite being used
          (for example, that the cryptographic algorithm is 128-bit AES and not
          256-bit AES).</test>
          <test>The following test is repeated for each supported certificate
          signing algorithm supported. The evaluator shall attempt to establish
          the connection using a server with a authentication server
          certificate that contains the Server Authentication purpose in the
          extendedKeyUsage field and verify that a connection is established.
          The evaluator will then verify that the client rejects an otherwise
          valid server certificate that lacks the Server Authentication purpose
          in the extendedKeyUsage field and a connection is not established.
          Ideally, the two certificates should be identical except for the
          extendedKeyUsage field.</test>
          <test>Following the guidance provided by the AGD guidance, a CA or an
          FQDN will be configured as ―acceptable‖ for authentication server
          certificates and then the evaluator will start a wireless connection
          and verify that the wireless client is able to successfully connect.
          The evaluator will then configure the system such that an otherwise
          valid certificate is signed by a CA that is not allowed by the TOE or
          presents a FQDN that is not allowed by the TOE. Attempts to
          authenticate to an authentication server presenting such a
          certificate should result in the connection being refused. If the TOE
          supports both methods of limiting the acceptable authentication
          servers, the evaluator shall repeat this test twice, once with each
          method.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure the authentication server to send
          a certificate in the TLS connection that the does not match the
          server-selected ciphersuite (for example, send a ECDSA certificate
          while using the TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA ciphersuite or send a
          RSA certificate while using one of the ECDSA ciphersuites.) The
          evaluator shall verify that the TOE disconnects after receiving the
          server‘s Certificate handshake message.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall setup a man-in-the-middle tool between the
          TOE and the authentication server and shall perform the following
          modifications to the traffic: 
          <ul>
            <li>Modify at least one byte in the server‘s nonce in the Server
            Hello handshake message, and verify that the server denies the
            client‘s Finished handshake message.</li>
            <li>Modify the server‘s selected ciphersuite in the Server Hello
            handshake message to be a ciphersuite not presented in the Client
            Hello handshake message. The evaluator shall verify that the client
            rejects the connection after receiving the Server Hello.</li>
            <li>(conditional) If a DHE or ECDHE ciphersuite is supported,
            modify the signature block in the Server‘s KeyExchange handshake
            message, and verify that the client rejects the connection after
            receiving the Server KeyExchange.</li>
            <li>Modify a byte in a CA field in the Server‘s Certificate Request
            handshake message. The modified CA field must not be the CA used to
            sign the client‘s certificate. The evaluator shall verify that the
            server rejects the connection after receiving the Client Finished
            handshake message.</li>
            <li>Modify a byte in the Server Finished handshake message, and
            verify that the client sends a fatal alert upon receipt and does
            not send any application data.</li>
          </ul></test>
        </testlist></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs_tls_ext.1.2" status="sel-based">
		<selection-depends req="ftp_dit_ext.1.1"/>
        <title>The application shall not establish a trusted channel if the
        distinguished name (DN) contained in a certificate does not match the
        expected DN for the peer.</title>
        <note role="application">The ciphersuites to be used in the evaluated
        configuration are limited by this requirement; however other
        ciphersuites may be implemented. The ST author should select the
        optional ciphersuites that are supported; if there are no ciphersuites
        supported other than the mandatory suites, then “None” should be
        selected. If administrative steps need to be taken so that the suites
        negotiated by the implementation are limited to those in this
        requirement, the appropriate instructions need to be contained in the
        guidance called for by AGD_OPE. 
        <p />The Suite B algorithms (RFC 6460) listed above are the preferred
        algorithms for implementation. <abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</abbr> 1.2 is the preferred protocol and
        may be required in the future. In addition, future publications of this
        PP will require that the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> offer a means to deny all connection
        attempts using specified older versions of the SSL/TLS protocol.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall check the description of the
        implementation of this protocol in the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> to ensure that the
        ciphersuites supported are specified. The evaluator shall check the TSS
        to ensure that the ciphersuites specified include those listed for this
        component. The evaluator shall also check the operational guidance to
        ensure that it contains instructions on configuring the TOE so that TLS
        conforms to the description in the TSS. The evaluator shall verify that
        the TSS describes how the DN in the certificate is compared to the
        expected DN. If the DN is not compared automatically to the Domain Name
        or IP address, the evaluator shall ensure that the AGD guidance
        includes configuration of the expected DN for the connection.
        Additional tests may be added in the future to test compliance with RFC
        5246. The evaluator shall also perform the following tests: 
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall establish a TLS connection using each of
          the ciphersuites specified by the requirement. This connection may be
          established as part of the establishment of a higher-level protocol,
          e.g., as part of an EAP session. It is sufficient to observe the
          successful negotiation of a ciphersuite to satisfy the intent of the
          test; it is not necessary to examine the characteristics of the
          encrypted traffic in an attempt to discern the ciphersuite being used
          (for example, that the cryptographic algorithm is 128-bit AES and not
          256-bit AES).</test>
          <test>The following test is repeated for each supported certificate
          signing algorithm supported. The evaluator shall attempt to establish
          the connection using a server with a server certificate that contains
          the Server Authentication purpose in the extendedKeyUsage field and
          verify that a connection is established. The evaluator will then
          verify that the client rejects an otherwise valid server certificate
          that lacks the Server Authentication purpose in the extendedKeyUsage
          field and a connection is not established. Ideally, the two
          certificates should be identical except for the extendedKeyUsage
          field.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall attempt a connection with a certificate
          where the DN matches either the configured expected DN or the Domain
          Name/IP address of the peer. The evaluator shall verify that the <abbr linkend="TSF" />
          is able to successfully connect. The evaluator shall attempt a
          connection with a certificate where the DN does not match either the
          configured expected DN or the Domain Name/IP address of the peer. The
          evaluator shall verify that the TSF is not able to successfully
          connect.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure the server to send a certificate
          in the TLS connection that the does not match the server-selected
          ciphersuite (for example, send a ECDSA certificate while using the
          TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA ciphersuite or send a RSA certificate
          while using one of the ECDSA ciphersuites.) The evaluator shall
          verify that the TOE disconnects after receiving the server‘s
          Certificate handshake message.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall setup a man-in-the-middle tool between the
          TOE and the server and shall perform the following modifications to
          the traffic: 
          <ul>
            <li>Modify at least one byte in the server‘s nonce in the Server
            Hello handshake message, and verify that the server denies the
            client‘s Finished handshake message.</li>
            <li>Modify the server‘s selected ciphersuite in the Server Hello
            handshake message to be a ciphersuite not presented in the Client
            Hello handshake ￼message. The evaluator shall verify that the
            client rejects the connection after receiving the Server
            Hello.</li>
            <li>(conditional) If a DHE or ECDHE ciphersuite is supported,
            modify the signature block in the Server‘s KeyExchange handshake
            message, and verify that the client rejects the connection after
            receiving the Server KeyExchange.</li>
            <li>Modify a byte in a CA field in the Server‘s Certificate Request
            handshake message. The modified CA field must not be the CA used to
            sign the client‘s certificate. The evaluator shall verify that the
            server rejects the connection after receiving the Client Finished
            handshake message.</li>
            <li>Modify a byte in the Server Finished handshake message, and
            verify that the client sends a fatal alert upon receipt and does
            not send any application data.</li>
          </ul></test>
        </testlist></aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>


  </subsection>
  <subsection title="Privacy (FPR)" id="fpr">
    <component id="fpr_ano_ext.1" name="Anonymous Network Behavior">
      <f-element id="fpr_ano_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must be capable of not transmitting any user
        identity information.</title>
        <note role="application">In-app ad-ware is subject to the same
        requirements as its host app regarding collection of information, and
        its behavior is evaluated as part of this requirement. 
        <!-- this is a problem since mobile adware is often provided via OS 
                                                                services --></note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall prepare a test environment which makes
        it possible to sniff network traffic between the platform and any
        remote systems. The evaluator shall install and run the application,
        and ensure that no PII is transmitted from the system.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
  </subsection>
  <subsection title="Trusted Path/Channel (FTP)" id="ftp">
    <component id="ftp_dit_ext.1" name="Protection of Data in Transit">
      <f-element id="ftp_dit_ext.1.1">
        <title>The <abbr linkend="TSF" /> must use 
        <selectables atleastone="yes">
          <selectable><abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</abbr></selectable>
          <selectable><abbr title="Datagram Transport Layer Security">DTLS</abbr></selectable>
          <selectable><abbr title="Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure">HTTPS</abbr></selectable>
        </selectables>to provide a communication channel to protect 
        <selectables>
          <selectable>all data</selectable>
          <selectable>all sensitive data</selectable>
        </selectables>transmitted between itself and another trusted <abbr title="information technology">IT</abbr>
        product.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall prepare a test environment which makes
        it possible to sniff network traffic between the platform and any
        remote systems. The evaluator shall install and run the application,
        and exercise its functionality. The evaluator shall ensure that
        transmitted data is protected as indicated in the
        selections.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
  </subsection>
  <subsection title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="fpt_api_ext">
    <component id="fpt_api_ext.1" name="Use of Supported Services and APIs">
      <f-element id="fpt_api_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must use platform-provided cryptographic
        libraries, unless providing cryptographic services is the purpose of
        the application.</title>
        <!-- subtly different AA here; search for non-platform crypto -->
        <aactivity>The developer must report the name and version of the
        cryptographic libraries used by the application. If a
        developer-designed cryptographic library is implemented, the evaluator
        shall verify that the library is FIPS certified.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <!-- TO DO: Hyperlink URLs. -->
      <f-element id="fpt_api_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application must use platform-provided libraries for parsing
        any structured files whose format is included in the IANA MIME media
        types as listed at http://www.iana.org/assignments/media-types, unless
        parsing services is the purpose of the application.</title>
        <note role="application">This includes many image, audio, video, and
        content file formats.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall ensure that the developer documentation
        specifies which structured file formats are parsed by the application,
        and which libraries are used to parse them. The evaluator shall verify
        that the libraries documented are provided by the platform.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_api_ext.1.3">
        <title>The application must not use any unsupported platform
        <abbr linkend="API" />s.</title>
        <aactivity>The developer must provide a list of operating system API
        functions used by the application. (Ideally, this list should be
        generated by the linker for the current build.) The evaluator shall
        then compare the developer-supplied list with the operating system
        documentation.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fpt_aex_ext.1" name="Anti-Exploitation Capabilities">
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application must not subvert address space layout
        randomization by requesting any memory mapping at an explicit
        address.</title>
        <aactivity> The evaluator shall ensure that the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> section of the ST describes 
        the compiler flag used to enable <addr linkend="ASLR" /> in the application. The evaluator shall perform 
        either a static or dynamic analysis to determine that no memory mappings are placed 
        at an explicit and consistent address. The method of doing so varies per platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">TBD</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall run the same
        program on two different andriod systems. Connect via ADB and inspect
        /proc/PID/maps. Ensure the two different instances share no mapping
        locations.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall run the same
        application on two different windows systems and run the Sysinternals
        tool VMMap on each system and verify the two different instances share
        no mapping locations.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall perform a static
        analysis to search for any mmap calls (or <abbr linkend="API" /> calls that call mmap),
        and ensure that no arguments are provided that request a mapping at a
        fixed address</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application must not subvert <abbr linkend="DEP" />
        by simultaneously allowing both write and execute permissions on any
        memory region.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine executable file headers to
        verify that platform supported DEP protections are enabled for the
        application.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.3">
        <title>The application must not subvert platform-provided heap
        corruption detection by implementing its own dynamic memory allocation
        functionality, unless that functionality also includes corruption
        detection.</title>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.4">
        <title>The application must be compatible with security features
        provided by the operating system vendor.</title>
        <note role="application">This requirement is designed to ensure that
        operating system features, or security enhancements provided by the
        operating system vendor, do not need to be disabled in order for the
        application to run.</note>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall carry out one of the following tests,
        depending on the platform. 
        <subaactivity platform="blackberry">TBD</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall ensure that the
        application can run with SE for Android enabled and in enforcement
        mode.</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall ensure that
        classis desktop applications and Windows Store applications are
        compatible with Microsoft's Enhanced Mitigation Experince Toolkit
        (EMET).</subaactivity>
        <subaactivity platform="ios">TBD</subaactivity></aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.5">The application must not write to
      directories that contain executable files. 
      <note role="application">If the application is specifically designed to
      produce executable files (such as a compiler), those files may be written
      to a specified directory from which execution is permitted.</note>
      <aactivity>The evaluator shall run the application and determine where
      all files are written. The evaluator shall determine whether the platform
      needs to execute files from that directory. This varies per platform: 
      <subaactivity platform="blackberry">The platform forces applications to
      write all data within the application working directory (sandbox), and so
      applications on this platform pass.</subaactivity>
      <subaactivity platform="android">The evaluator shall run the program and
      note where all files are written. The evaluator shall ensure that there
      are no executable files stored within the applications data
      directory.</subaactivity>
      <subaactivity platform="windows">The evaluator shall run the program and
      note where all files are written. The evaluator shall ensure that it is
      not possible to also execute files from these locations.</subaactivity>
      <subaactivity platform="ios">The platform forces applications to write
      all data within the application working directory (sandbox), and so
      applications on this platform
      pass.</subaactivity></aactivity></f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.6">
        <title>The application must not subvert stack cookie protections by
        disabling default compiler options.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall ensure that the application was compiled
        with the stack cookie security feature not disabled.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fpt_tud_ext.1" name="Integrity for Installation and Update">
      <!-- TO DO: Cite references. -->
      <f-element id="fpt_tud_ext.1.1">
        <title>The application installation and update packages must be signed
        by the vendor in conformance with NIST SP 800-89, Recommendation for
        Obtaining Assurances for Digital Signature Applications, using an
        approved digital signature algorithm as specified in NIST FIPS 186-3,
        Digital Signature Standard, that provides at least 112 bits of security
        strength, in accordance with NIST SP 800-131A, Transitions:
        Recommendation for Transitioning the Use of Cryptographic Algorithms
        and Key Lengths.</title>
        <note role="application">Signatures of signed installation and update
        packages should be verified by the operating system's application
        installation mechanism. Since the existence of such a mechanism is a
        requirement on the operating system (and not the application), it is
        not specified here.</note>
        <aactivity>Developers must document their process for cryptographically
        signing updates and installation packages. The evaluator shall verify
        that the documentation conforms with the above requirement.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_tud_ext.1.2">
        <title>The application update and installation packages must be
        distributed using the format of the operating system-supported package
        manager.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall verify that application updates are
        distributed in a format supported by a standard mechanism. Examples of
        standard mechanisms include: The BlackBerry World storefront,
        BlackBerry World for Work storefront, BlackBerry Administration
        Service, Standard Windows Installer (.msi) format, Windows App Store
        package (.appx), Google Play Store (.apk) or OEM App Store,
        Enterprise-run Android App store, The Apple App Store, Enterprise-run
        iOS App repositories.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_tud_ext.1.3">
        <title>The application must be packaged such that its removal results
        in the removal of all traces of the application.  Configuration, preference settings, and audit or log events may remain.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall uninstall the application and search for
        evidence of the uninstalled application on the platform.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
    <component id="fpt_idv_ext.1" name="Software Identification and Versions">
      <f-element id="fpt_idv_ext.1.1" status="objective" targetdate="January 1, 2015">
        <title>The application must include <abbr title="Software Identification">SWID</abbr> tags
        that comply with the ISO/IEC 19770-2:2009 standard.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install the application, then check for
        the existence of SWID tags that comply with the ISO/IEC 19770-2:2009
        standard.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fpt_idv_ext.1.2">
        <title>The applications must present correct product version
        information.</title>
        <aactivity>The evaluator shall install the application and identify its
        version.</aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </component>
  </subsection></section>
  <section title="Security Assurance Requirements" id="SARs">The Security
  Objectives for the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> in 
  <secref linkend="req" />were constructed to address threats identified in 
  <secref linkend="threats" />. <abbr linkend="SFR" />s in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />are a formal instantiation of the Security
  Objectives. The PP draws from <abbr title="Evaluation Assurance Level">EAL</abbr>1 the <abbr linkend="SAR" />s)
  to frame the extent to which the evaluator assesses the documentation
  applicable for the evaluation and performs independent testing. 
  <br />While this section contains the complete set of SARs from the CC, the
  Assurance Activities to be performed by an evaluator are detailed in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />as well as in this section. The general model for
  evaluation of TOEs against STs written to conform to this PP is as follows: 
  <br />After the ST has been approved for evaluation, the <abbr class="expanded" title="Information Technology Security Evaluation Facility">ITSEF</abbr> will obtain
  the TOE, supporting environmental IT, and the administrative guides for the
  TOE. The Assurance Activities listed in the ST (which will be refined by the
  ITSEF to be TOE-specific, either within the ST or in a separate document)
  will then be performed by the ITSEF. The ITSEF is also expected to perform
  all of the actions mandated by the <cite linkend="CEM" /> for
  EAL1. The results of these activities will be documented and presented (along
  with the administrative guidance used) for validation. 
  <br />For each family, "Developer Notes" are provided on the developer action
  elements to clarify what, if any, additional documentation/activity needs to
  be provided by the developer. For the content/presentation and evaluator
  activity elements, additional assurance activities (to those already
  contained in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />and the CEM for EAL1) are described as a whole for
  the family rather than for each element. Additionally, the assurance
  activities described in this section are complementary to those specified in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />. 
  <br />The TOE security assurance requirements, summarized in the table below,
  identify the management and evaluative activities required to meet the
  objectives identified in 
  <secref linkend="obj" />of this PP. 
  <!-- Generate a table here, based on the next sections -->
  <subsection title="Class ASE: Security Target" id="ase">As per ASE activities
  defined in 
  <cite linkend="bibCEM" />.</subsection>
  <subsection title="Class ADV: Development" id="adv">The information about the
  <abbr linkend="TOE" /> is contained in the guidance documentation available to the end user as
  well as the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> portion of the ST. The TOE
  developer must concur with the description of the product that is contained
  in the TSS as it relates to the functional requirements. The Assurance
  Activities contained in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />should provide the ST authors with sufficient
  information to determine the appropriate content for the TSS section. 
  <component id="adv_upd_ext.1" name="Support for Updates (ADV_UPD_EXT.1)">
    <a-element id="adv_upd_ext.1.1">
      <title>Application developers must support update of their products for
      purposes of fixing security vulnerabilities.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="adv_upd_ext.1.2">
      <title>Application update must not change the security properties or
      configuration of the product without notifying the user of the specific
      changes.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="adv_upd_ext.1.3">
      <title>Application developers must commit to supporting their
      applications with updates for a publicly documented period of
      time.</title>
    </a-element>
  </component>
  <component id="adv_fsp.1" name="Basic Functional Specification (ADV_FSP.1)">The
  functional specification describes the <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>s. 
  It is not necessary to have a formal or complete specification of
  these interfaces. Additionally, because <abbr linkend="TOE" />s conforming to this PP will
  necessarily have interfaces to the Operational Environment that are not
  directly invokable by TOE users, there is little point specifying that such
  interfaces be described in and of themselves since only indirect testing of
  such interfaces may be possible. For this PP, the activities for this family
  should focus on understanding the interfaces presented in the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> in response
  to the functional requirements and the interfaces presented in the AGD
  documentation. No additional “functional specification” documentation is
  necessary to satisfy the assurance activities specified. The interfaces that
  need to be evaluated are characterized through the information needed to
  perform the assurance activities listed, rather than as an independent,
  abstract list. 
  <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1D">
    <title>The developer shall provide a functional specification.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2D">
    <title>The developer shall provide a tracing from the functional
    specification to the SFRs.</title>
    <note role="application">As indicated in the introduction to this section,
    the functional specification is comprised of the information contained in
    the AGD_OPE and AGD_PRE documentation. The developer may reference a
    website accessible to application developers and the evaluator. The
    assurance activities in the functional requirements point to evidence that
    should exist in the documentation and <abbr linkend="TSS" /> section; since these are directly
    associated with the SFRs, the tracing in element ADV_FSP.1.2D is implicitly
    already done and no additional documentation is necessary.</note>
  </a-element>
  <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1C">
    <title>The functional specification shall describe the purpose and method
    of use for each SFR-enforcing and SFR-supporting <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2C">
    <title>The functional specification shall identify all parameters
    associated with each SFR-enforcing and SFR-supporting <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.3C">
    <title>The functional specification shall provide rationale for the
    implicit categorization of interfaces as SFR-non-interfering.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.4C">
    <title>The tracing shall demonstrate that the SFRs trace to <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>s in the
    functional specification.</title>
  </a-element>
  <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1E">
    <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all
    requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2E">
    <title>The evaluator shall determine that the functional specification is
    an accurate and complete instantiation of the SFRs.</title>
    <aactivity>There are no specific assurance activities associated with these
    SARs, except ensuring the information is provided. The functional
    specification documentation is provided to support the evaluation
    activities described in 
    <secref linkend="SFRs" />, and other activities described for AGD, ATE, and
    AVA SARs. The requirements on the content of the functional specification
    information is implicitly assessed by virtue of the other assurance
    activities being performed; if the evaluator is unable to perform an
    activity because the there is insufficient interface information, then an
    adequate functional specification has not been provided.</aactivity>
  </a-element></component></subsection>
  <subsection id="agd" title="Class AGD: Guidance Documentation">The guidance
  documents will be provided with the ST. Guidance must include a description
  of how the IT personnel verifies that the Operational Environment can fulfill
  its role for the security functionality. The documentation should be in an
  informal style and readable by the IT personnel. Guidance must be provided
  for every operational environment that the product supports as claimed in the
  ST. This guidance includes Instructions to successfully install the <abbr linkend="TSF" /> in
  that environment; and Instructions to manage the security of the TSF as a
  product and as a component of the larger operational environment. Guidance
  pertaining to particular security functionality is also provided;
  requirements on such guidance are contained in the assurance activities
  specified with each requirement. 
  <component id="agd_ope.1" name="Operational User Guidance (AGD_OPE.1)">
    <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1D">
      <title>The developer shall provide operational user guidance.</title>
      <note role="application">The operation user guidance does not have to be
      contained in a single document. Guidance to users, administrators and
      application developers can be spread among documents or web pages. Where
      appropriate, the guidance documentation is expressed in the eXtensible
      Configuration Checklist Description Format (XCCDF) to support security
      automation. Rather than repeat information here, the developer should
      review the assurance activities for this component to ascertain the
      specifics of the guidance that the evaluator will be checking for. This
      will provide the necessary information for the preparation of acceptable
      guidance.</note>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role,
      the user-accessible functions and privileges that should be controlled in
      a secure processing environment, including appropriate warnings.</title>
      <note role="application">User and administrator are to be considered in
      the definition of user role.</note>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.2C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role,
      how to use the available interfaces provided by the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> in a secure
      manner.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.3C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role,
      the available functions and interfaces, in particular all security
      parameters under the control of the user, indicating secure values as
      appropriate.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.4C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall, for each user role, clearly
      present each type of security-relevant event relative to the
      user-accessible functions that need to be performed, including changing
      the security characteristics of entities under the control of the
      <abbr linkend="TSF" />.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.5C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall identify all possible modes of
      operation of the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> (including operation following failure or
      operational error), their consequences, and implications for maintaining
      secure operation.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.6C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall, for each user role, describe
      the security measures to be followed in order to fulfill the security
      objectives for the operational environment as described in the
      ST.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.7C">
      <title>The operational user guidance shall be clear and
      reasonable.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1E">
      <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets
      all requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
      <aactivity>Some of the contents of the operational guidance will be
      verified by the assurance activities in 
      <secref linkend="SFRs" />and evaluation of the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> according to the <cite linkend="CEM" />.
      The following additional information is also required. If cryptographic
      functions are provided by the TOE, the operational guidance shall contain
      instructions for configuring the cryptographic engine associated with the
      evaluated configuration of the TOE. It shall provide a warning to the
      administrator that use of other cryptographic engines was not evaluated
      nor tested during the CC evaluation of the TOE. The documentation must
      describe the process for verifying updates to the TOE by verifying a
      digital signature – this may be done by the TOE or the underlying
      platform. The evaluator shall verify that this process includes the
      following steps: Instructions for obtaining the update itself. This
      should include instructions for making the update accessible to the TOE
      (e.g., placement in a specific directory). Instructions for initiating
      the update process, as well as discerning whether the process was
      successful or unsuccessful. This includes generation of the hash/digital
      signature. The TOE will likely contain security functionality that does
      not fall in the scope of evaluation under this PP. The operational
      guidance shall make it clear to an administrator which security
      functionality is covered by the evaluation activities.</aactivity>
    </a-element>
  </component>
  <component id="agd_pre.1" name="Preparative Procedures (AGD_PRE.1)">
    <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1D">
      <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="TOE" />, including its preparative
      procedures.</title>
      <note role="application">As with the operational guidance, the developer
      should look to the assurance activities to determine the required content
      with respect to preparative procedures.</note>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1C">
      <title>The preparative procedures shall describe all the steps necessary
      for secure acceptance of the delivered <abbr linkend="TOE" /> in accordance with the
      developer's delivery procedures.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.2C">
      <title>The preparative procedures shall describe all the steps necessary
      for secure installation of the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> and for the secure preparation of the
      operational environment in accordance with the security objectives for
      the operational environment as described in the ST.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1E">
      <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets
      all requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.2E">
      <title>The evaluator shall apply the preparative procedures to confirm
      that the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> can be prepared securely for operation.</title>
      <aactivity>As indicated in the introduction above, there are significant
      expectations with respect to the documentation—especially when
      configuring the operational environment to support TOE functional
      requirements. The evaluator shall check to ensure that the guidance
      provided for the TOE adequately addresses all platforms claimed for the
      TOE in the ST.</aactivity>
    </a-element>
  </component></subsection>
  <subsection id="alc" title="Class ALC: Life-cycle Support">
    <component id="alc_cmc.1" name="Labeling of the TOE (ALC_CMC.1)">This component is
    targeted at identifying the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> such that it can be distinguished from
    other products or versions from the same vendor and can be easily specified
    when being procured by an end user. 
    <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1d">
      <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> and a reference for the
      TOE.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1c">
      <title>The <abbr linkend="TOE" /> shall be labeled with a unique reference.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1e">
      <title>The evaluator 
      <i>shall confirm</i>that the information provided meets all requirements
      for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
      <aactivity>The evaluator shall check the ST to ensure that it contains an
      identifier (such as a product name/version number) that specifically
      identifies the version that meets the requirements of the ST. Further,
      the evaluator shall check the AGD guidance and <abbr linkend="TOE" /> samples received for
      testing to ensure that the version number is consistent with that in the
      ST. If the vendor maintains a web site advertising the TOE, the evaluator
      shall examine the information on the web site to ensure that the
      information in the ST is sufficient to distinguish the
      product.</aactivity>
    </a-element></component>
    <component id="alc_cms.1" name="TOE CM Coverage (ALC_CMS.1)">Given the scope of the <abbr linkend="TOE" />
    and its associated evaluation evidence requirements, this component’s
    assurance activities are covered by the assurance activities listed for
    ALC_CMC.1. 
    <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1d">
      <title>The developer shall provide a configuration list for the
      <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1c">
      <title>The configuration list shall include the following: the <abbr linkend="TOE" />
      itself; and the evaluation evidence required by the SARs.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="alc_cms.1.2c">
      <title>The configuration list shall uniquely identify the configuration
      items.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1e">
      <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets
      all requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
      <aactivity>The "evaluation evidence required by the SARs" in this PP is
      limited to the information in the ST coupled with the guidance provided
      to administrators and users under the AGD requirements. By ensuring that
      the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> is specifically identified and that this identification is
      consistent in the ST and in the AGD guidance (as done in the assurance
      activity for ALC_CMC.1), the evaluator implicitly confirms the
      information required by this component. Life-cycle support is targeted
      aspects of the developer’s life-cycle and instructions to providers of
      applications for the developer’s devices, rather than an in-depth
      examination of the <abbr linkend="TSF" /> manufacturer’s development and configuration
      management process. This is not meant to diminish the critical role that
      a developer’s practices play in contributing to the overall
      trustworthiness of a product; rather, it’s a reflection on the
      information to be made available for evaluation. 
      <br />The evaluator shall ensure that the developer has identified (in
      public-facing development documentation for their platform) one or more
      development environments appropriate for use in developing applications
      for the developer’s platform. For each of these development environments,
      the developer shall provide information on how to configure the
      environment to ensure that buffer overflow protection mechanisms in the
      environment(s) are invoked (e.g., compiler flags). The evaluator shall
      ensure that this documentation also includes an indication of whether
      such protections are on by default, or have to be specifically enabled.
      The evaluator shall ensure that the TSF is uniquely identified (with
      respect to other products from the TSF vendor), and that documentation
      provided by the developer in association with the requirements in the ST
      is associated with the TSF using this unique identification.</aactivity>
    </a-element></component>
  </subsection>
  <subsection id="ate" title="Class ATE: Tests">Testing is specified for
  functional aspects of the system as well as aspects that take advantage of
  design or implementation weaknesses. The former is done through the ATE_IND
  family, while the latter is through the AVA_VAN family. At the assurance
  level specified in this PP, testing is based on advertised functionality and
  interfaces with dependency on the availability of design information. One of
  the primary outputs of the evaluation process is the test report as specified
  in the following requirements. 
  <component id="ate_ind.1" name="Independent Testing – Conformance (ATE_IND.1)">
  Testing is performed to confirm the functionality described in the <abbr linkend="TSS" /> as
  well as the administrative (including configuration and operational)
  documentation provided. The focus of the testing is to confirm that the
  requirements specified in 
  <secref linkend="SFRs" />being met, although some additional testing is
  specified for SARs in 
  <secref linkend="SARs" />. The Assurance Activities identify the additional
  testing activities associated with these components. The evaluator produces a
  test report documenting the plan for and results of testing, as well as
  coverage arguments focused on the platform/<abbr linkend="TOE" /> combinations that are claiming
  conformance to this PP. Given the scope of the TOE and its associated
  evaluation evidence requirements, this component’s assurance activities are
  covered by the assurance activities listed for ALC_CMC.1. 
  <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1d">
    <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> for testing.</title>
  </a-element>
  <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1c">
    <title>The configuration list shall include the following: the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> itself;
    and the evaluation evidence required by the SARs.</title>
  </a-element>
  <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
  <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1e">
    <title>The evaluator 
    <i>shall confirm</i>that the information provided meets all requirements
    for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
  </a-element>
  <a-element id="ate_ind.1.2e">
    <title>The evaluator 
    <i>shall test</i>a subset of the <abbr linkend="TSF" /> to confirm that the <abbr linkend="TSF" /> operates as
    specified.</title>
    <aactivity>The evaluator shall prepare a test plan and report documenting
    the testing aspects of the system. The test plan covers all of the testing
    actions contained in the <cite linkend="CEM" /> and the body of this PP’s Assurance
    Activities. While it is not necessary to have one test case per test listed
    in an Assurance Activity, the evaluator must document in the test plan that
    each applicable testing requirement in the ST is covered. The test plan
    identifies the platforms to be tested, and for those platforms not included
    in the test plan but included in the ST, the test plan provides a
    justification for not testing the platforms. This justification must
    address the differences between the tested platforms and the untested
    platforms, and make an argument that the differences do not affect the
    testing to be performed. It is not sufficient to merely assert that the
    differences have no affect; rationale must be provided. If all platforms
    claimed in the ST are tested, then no rationale is necessary. The test plan
    describes the composition of each platform to be tested, and any setup that
    is necessary beyond what is contained in the AGD documentation. It should
    be noted that the evaluator is expected to follow the AGD documentation for
    installation and setup of each platform either as part of a test or as a
    standard pre-test condition. This may include special test drivers or
    tools. For each driver or tool, an argument (not just an assertion) should
    be provided that the driver or tool will not adversely affect the
    performance of the functionality by the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> and its platform. This also
    includes the configuration of the cryptographic engine to be used. The
    cryptographic algorithms implemented by this engine are those specified by
    this PP and used by the cryptographic protocols being evaluated (IPsec,
    TLS/HTTPS, SSH). The test plan identifies high-level test objectives as
    well as the test procedures to be followed to achieve those objectives.
    These procedures include expected results. The test report (which could
    just be an annotated version of the test plan) details the activities that
    took place when the test procedures were executed, and includes the actual
    results of the tests. This shall be a cumulative account, so if there was a
    test run that resulted in a failure; a fix installed; and then a successful
    re-run of the test, the report would show a “fail” and “pass” result (and
    the supporting details), and not just the “pass” result.</aactivity>
  </a-element></component></subsection>
  <subsection id="ava" title="Class AVA: Vulnerability Assessment">For the
  first generation of this protection profile, the evaluation lab is expected
  to survey open sources to discover what vulnerabilities have been discovered
  in these types of products. In most cases, these vulnerabilities will require
  sophistication beyond that of a basic attacker. Until penetration tools are
  created and uniformly distributed to the evaluation labs, the evaluator will
  not be expected to test for these vulnerabilities in the <abbr linkend="TOE" />. The labs will
  be expected to comment on the likelihood of these vulnerabilities given the
  documentation provided by the vendor. This information will be used in the
  development of penetration testing tools and for the development of future
  protection profiles. 
  <component id="ava_van.1" name="Vulnerability Survey (AVA_VAN.1)">
    <h4>Developer action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AVA_VAN.1.1D">
      <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> for testing.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Content and presentation elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AVA_VAN.1.1C">
      <title>The <abbr linkend="TOE" /> shall be suitable for testing.</title>
    </a-element>
    <h4>Evaluator action elements:</h4>
    <a-element id="AVA_VAN.1.1E">
      <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets
      all requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AVA_VAN.1.2E">
      <title>The evaluator shall perform a search of public domain sources to
      identify potential vulnerabilities in the <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</title>
    </a-element>
    <a-element id="AVA_VAN.1.3E">
      <title>The evaluator shall conduct penetration testing, based on the
      identified potential vulnerabilities, to determine that the <abbr linkend="TOE" /> is
      resistant to attacks performed by an attacker possessing Basic attack
      potential.</title>
      <aactivity>As with ATE_IND, the evaluator shall generate a report to
      document their findings with respect to this requirement. This report
      could physically be part of the overall test report mentioned in ATE_IND,
      or a separate document. The evaluator performs a search of public
      information to determine the vulnerabilities that have been found in
      network infrastructure devices and the implemented communication
      protocols in general, as well as those that pertain to the particular
      TOE. The evaluator documents the sources consulted and the
      vulnerabilities found in the report. For each vulnerability found, the
      evaluator either provides a rationale with respect to its
      non-applicability, or the evaluator formulates a test (using the
      guidelines provided in ATE_IND) to confirm the vulnerability, if
      suitable. Suitability is determined by assessing the attack vector needed
      to take advantage of the vulnerability. If exploiting the vulnerability
      requires expert skills and an electron microscope, for instance, then a
      test would not be suitable and an appropriate justification would be
      formulated.</aactivity>
    </a-element>
  </component></subsection></section></chapter>

  <appendix title="NIST SP 800-53/CNSS 1253 Mapping" id="nistmapping">Here is a
  placeholder for a table with references to <abbr title="National Institute of Standards and Technology">NIST</abbr> controls. This would indicate
  which controls are implemented (and thus have been tested) in products that
  are successfully evaluated. This is in keeping with Appendix H of NIST SP
  800-53 "International Information Security Standards," which states 
  <i>organizations can obtain significant benefit from the acquisition and
  employment of information technology products evaluated against the
  requirements of ISO/IEC 15408. The use of such products can provide evidence
  that certain security controls are implemented correctly, operating as
  intended, and producing the desired effect in satisfying stated security
  requirements.</i>Its Table H.3 provides a mapping between Common Criteria
  (ISO/IEC 15408) controls and the controls in 800-53.</appendix>
  <appendix title="References" id="biblio">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
        Evaluation - 
        <ul>
          <li>Part 1: Introduction and General Model, 
CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
          <li>Part 2: Security Functional Components, 
CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
          <li>Part 3: Security Assurance Components, 
CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012</li>
        </ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology
        Security - Evaluation Methodology, CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September 2012</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <tag>CESG</tag>
        <description>CESG - 
        <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/end-user-devices-security-guidance">
        End User Devices Security and Configuration Guidance</a></description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
</PP>
