<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions  xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
		      xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
  <bunch>
    <applies-to max-inclusive="1.3" name="Protection Profile for Application Software"/>

    <decision id='0435'>
    	<notes>Alternative to SELinux for FPT_AEX_EXT.1.3</notes>

        <change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fpt_aex_ext.1.3']" mode="replace">
          <f-element id="fpt_aex_ext.1.3">
            <title>The application shall be compatible with security features provided by the
              platform vendor.</title>
            <note role="application">This requirement is designed to ensure that platform security 
              features do not need to be disabled in order for the application to run.</note>
            <aactivity>
	      <TSS/>None.
              <Guidance/>None.
              <Tests/>The evaluator shall configure the platform in the ascribed manner and 
	      carry out one of the prescribed tests:
	                    <subaactivity platform="android">Applications running on Android cannot disable Android 
                security features, therefore this requirement is met and no evaluation activity is required.
	      </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="windows">If the OS platform supports Windows Defender Exploit Guard 
                (Windows 10 version 1709 or later), then the evaluator shall ensure that the application can 
                run successfully with Windows Defender Exploit Guard Exploit Protection configured with the 
                following minimum mitigations enabled; Control Flow Guard (CFG), Randomize memory allocations 
                (Bottom-Up ASLR), Export address filtering (EAF), Import address filtering (IAF), and
                Data Execution Prevention (DEP). The following link describes how to enable Exploit Protection, 
                https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/security/threat-protection/windows-defender-exploit-guard/customize-exploit-protection.
                <br/>
                If the OS platform supports the Enhanced Mitigation Experience Toolkit (EMET) which can be 
                installed on Windows 10 version 1703 and earlier, then the evaluator shall ensure that 
                the application can run successfully with EMET configured with the following minimum 
                mitigations enabled; Memory Protection Check, Randomize memory allocations (Bottom-Up ASLR), 
                Export address filtering (EAF), and Data Execution Prevention (DEP).
              </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="ios">Applications running on iOS cannot disable
                security features, therefore this requirement is met and no evaluation activity is required.
              </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="linux"> The evaluator shall ensure that the application can
                successfully run on a system with either SELinux or AppArmor enabled and in enforce mode.
	      </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="Solaris">
		The evaluator shall ensure that the application can run with 
		Solaris Trusted Extensions enabled and enforcing.
	      </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="mac"> The evaluator shall ensure that the application can
                successfully run on macOS without disabling any security features. </subaactivity>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
	</change>
    </decision>
  </bunch>
</technical-decisions>
