<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions  xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
		      xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
  <bunch>
    <applies-to max-inclusive="1.3" name="Protection Profile for Application Software"/>

    <decision id='0434'>
    	<notes>Windows Desktop Applications Test</notes>

        <change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fdp_dec_ext.1.1']" mode="replace">
          <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.1">
            <title> The application shall restrict its access to
              <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>no hardware resources</selectable>
                <selectable>network connectivity</selectable>
                <selectable>camera</selectable>
                <selectable>microphone</selectable>
                <selectable>location services</selectable>
                <selectable><h:abbr title="Near-Field Communication">NFC</h:abbr></selectable>
                <selectable><h:abbr title="Universal Serial Bus">USB</h:abbr></selectable>
                <selectable>Bluetooth</selectable>
                <selectable><assignable>list of additional hardware resources</assignable></selectable>
              </selectables>.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              The intent is for the evaluator to ensure that the selection captures all
              hardware resources which the application accesses, and that these are 
			  restricted to those which are justified.
			  On some platforms, the application must explicitly solicit permission 
			  in order to access hardware resources.
			  Seeking such permissions, even if the application does not later make use of the
			  hardware resource, should still be considered access.
			  Selections should be expressed in a manner consistent with how the application expresses
			  its access needs to the underlying platform.  For example,
			  the platform may provide <h:i>location services</h:i> which implies the potential use of a variety
			  of hardware resources (e.g. satellite receivers, WiFi, cellular radio)
			  yet <h:i>location services</h:i> is the proper selection.  This is because use of these resources
			  can be inferred, but also because the actual usage may vary based on the particular platform.
              Resources that do not need to be explicitly identified are
              those which are ordinarily used by any application such as central processing units,
			  main memory, displays, input devices (e.g. keyboards, mice), and
			  persistent storage devices provided by the platform.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
                <TSS/>None.
              <Guidance/>The evaluator shall perform the platform-specific actions below and inspect user
              documentation to determine the application's access to hardware
              resources.  The evaluator shall ensure that this is consistent with the selections
              indicated.  The evaluator shall review documentation provided by the application
              developer and for each resource which it accesses, identify the
              justification as to why access is required.  
              <Tests/>
              <subaactivity platform="android">
                The evaluator shall inspect permissions presented at 
                installation time (Android 5.1 and below) or on-access 
                (Android 6.0 and above) for each hardware resource an app intends 
                to access.  
              </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="windows">For Windows Universal Applications the evaluator shall check the
                WMAppManifest.xml file for a list of required hardware capabilities. The evaluator
                shall verify that the user is made aware of the required hardware capabilities when
                the application is first installed. This includes permissions such as
                ID_CAP_ISV_CAMERA, ID_CAP_LOCATION, ID_CAP_NETWORKING, ID_CAP_MICROPHONE,
                ID_CAP_PROXIMITY and so on.
		A complete list of Windows App permissions can be found
                at: 
		<h:ul><h:li>
		  <h:a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx">
                    http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx
		  </h:a>
		</h:li></h:ul>
		        For Windows Desktop Applications the evaluator shall identify in either the
                application software or its documentation the list of the required
                hardware resources. 
                </subaactivity>
                <subaactivity platform="ios">The evaluator shall verify that either the
                  application or the documentation provides a list of the
                  hardware resources it accesses. </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="linux"> The evaluator shall verify that either the
                application software or its documentation provides a list of the
                hardware resources it accesses. </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="Solaris"> The evaluator shall verify that either the
                application software or its documentation provides a list of the
                hardware resources it accesses. </subaactivity>
              <subaactivity platform="mac"> The evaluator shall verify that either the application
                software or its documentation provides a list of the hardware
                resources it accesses.</subaactivity>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
	</change>
    </decision>
  </bunch>
</technical-decisions>
