<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> <bunch> <applies-to name="Protection Profile for Application Software" max-inclusive="1.3">  </applies-to><decision id="0515"> <notes> Use Android APK manifest in test </notes>
<change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fdp_dec_ext.1.1']" mode="replace"> 
          <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.1"> 
            <title> 
              The application shall restrict its access to 
              <selectables linebreak="yes"> 
                <selectable> no hardware resources </selectable>
                <selectable> network connectivity </selectable>
                <selectable> camera </selectable>
                <selectable> microphone </selectable>
                <selectable> location services </selectable>
                <selectable> 
                  <h:abbr title="Near-Field Communication"> NFC </h:abbr>
                 </selectable>
                <selectable> 
                  <h:abbr title="Universal Serial Bus"> USB </h:abbr>
                 </selectable>
                <selectable> Bluetooth </selectable>
                <selectable> 
                  <assignable> list of additional hardware resources </assignable>
                 </selectable> </selectables>
              .
             </title>
            <note role="application"> 
              The intent is for the evaluator to ensure that the selection captures all hardware resources
              which the application accesses, and that these are restricted to those which are justified. On
              some platforms, the application must explicitly solicit permission in order to access
              hardware resources. Seeking such permissions, even if the application does not later make use
              of the hardware resource, should still be considered access. Selections should be expressed
              in a manner consistent with how the application expresses its access needs to the underlying
              platform. For example, the platform may provide 
              <h:i> location services </h:i>
              which implies the potential use of a variety of hardware resources (e.g. satellite receivers,
              WiFi, cellular radio) yet 
              <h:i> location services </h:i>
              is the proper selection. This is because use of these resources can be inferred, but also
              because the actual usage may vary based on the particular platform. Resources that do not need
              to be explicitly identified are those which are ordinarily used by any application such as
              central processing units, main memory, displays, input devices (e.g. keyboards, mice), and
              persistent storage devices provided by the platform.
             </note>
            <aactivity> 
              <TSS> None. </TSS>
              <Guidance> 
                The evaluator shall perform the platform-specific actions below and inspect user
                documentation to determine the application's access to hardware resources. The evaluator
                shall ensure that this is consistent with the selections indicated. The evaluator shall
                review documentation provided by the application developer and for each resource which it
                accesses, identify the justification as to why access is required.
               </Guidance>
              <Tests> 
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> android </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that each <uses-permission>entry in the AndroidManifest.xml file for access to a hardware resource is reflected in the selection.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> windows </ref-id> </depends>
                  For Windows Universal Applications the evaluator shall check the WMAppManifest.xml file for
                  a list of required hardware capabilities. The evaluator shall verify that the user is made
                  aware of the required hardware capabilities when the application is first installed. This
                  includes permissions such as ID_CAP_ISV_CAMERA, ID_CAP_LOCATION, ID_CAP_NETWORKING,
                  ID_CAP_MICROPHONE, ID_CAP_PROXIMITY and so on. A complete list of Windows App permissions
                  can be found at: 
                  <h:ul> 
                    <h:li> 
                      <h:a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx"> 
                        http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx
                       </h:a>
                     </h:li>
                   </h:ul>
                  For Windows Desktop Applications the evaluator shall identify in either the application
                  software or its documentation the list of the required hardware resources.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> ios </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application or the documentation provides a list of
                  the hardware resources it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> linux </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of the hardware resources it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> Solaris </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of the hardware resources it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> mac </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of the hardware resources it accesses.
                 </h:p>
               </Tests> </aactivity> </f-element> </change> 

<change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fdp_dec_ext.1.2']" mode="replace"> 
          <f-element id="fdp_dec_ext.1.2"> 
            <title> 
              The application shall restrict its access to 
              <selectables linebreak="yes"> 
                <selectable> no sensitive information repositories </selectable>
                <selectable> address book </selectable>
                <selectable> calendar </selectable>
                <selectable> call lists </selectable>
                <selectable> system logs </selectable>
                <selectable> 
                  <assignable> 
                    list of additional sensitive information repositories
                   </assignable>
                 </selectable> </selectables>
              .
             </title>
            <note role="application"> 
              <h:i> Sensitive information repositories </h:i>
              are defined as those collections of sensitive data that could be expected to be shared among
              some applications, users, or user roles, but to which not all of these would ordinarily require
              access.
             </note>
            <aactivity> 
              <TSS> None. </TSS><Guidance> 
                The evaluator shall perform the platform-specific actions below and inspect user
                documentation to determine the application's access to sensitive information
                repositories. The evaluator shall ensure that this is consistent with the selections
                indicated. The evaluator shall review documentation provided by the application developer
                and for each sensitive information repository which it accesses, identify the justification
                as to why access is required.
               </Guidance><Tests> 
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> android </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that each <uses-permission>entry in the AndroidManifest.xml file for access to a sensitive information repository is reflected in the selection.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> windows </ref-id> </depends>
                  For Windows Universal Applications the evaluator shall check the WMAppManifest.xml file for
                  a list of required capabilities. The evaluator shall identify the required information
                  repositories when the application is first installed. This includes permissions such as
                  ID_CAP_CONTACTS,ID_CAP_APPOINTMENTS,ID_CAP_MEDIALIB and so on. A complete list of
                  Windows App permissions can be found at: 
                  <h:ul> 
                    <h:li> 
                      <h:a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx"> 
                        http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-US/library/windows/apps/jj206936.aspx
                       </h:a>
                     </h:li>
                   </h:ul>
                  For Windows Desktop Applications the evaluator shall identify in either the application
                  software or its documentation the list of sensitive information repositories it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> ios </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of the sensitive information repositories it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> linux </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of sensitive information repositories it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> Solaris </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of sensitive information repositories it accesses.
                 </h:p>
                <h:p> 
                  <depends on="selection"> <ref-id> mac </ref-id> </depends>
                  The evaluator shall verify that either the application software or its documentation
                  provides a list of sensitive information repositories it accesses.
                 </h:p>
               </Tests> </aactivity> </f-element> </change>
</decision> </bunch> </technical-decisions>