<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> <bunch> <applies-to name="Protection Profile for Application Software" max-inclusive="1.3">  </applies-to><decision id="0554"> <notes> iOS/iPadOS/Android AppSW Virus Scan </notes><change xpath=".//a-component[@id='ava_van.1']" mode="replace"> <a-component id="ava_van.1" name="Vulnerability Survey (AVA_VAN.1)"> 
          <h:h4> Developer action elements: </h:h4>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.1d"> 
            <title> 
              The developer shall provide the 
              <abbr linkend="TOE" title="Target of Evaluation"> TOE </abbr>
              for testing.
             </title> </a-element>
          <h:h4> Content and presentation elements: </h:h4>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.1c"> 
            <title> 
              The application shall be suitable for testing.
             </title>
            <note role="application"> 
              Suitability for testing means not being obfuscated or packaged in such a way as to disrupt
              either static or dynamic analysis by the evaluator.
             </note> </a-element>
          <h:h4> Evaluator action elements: </h:h4>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.1e"> 
            <title> 
              The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements for content
              and presentation of evidence.
             </title> </a-element>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.2e"> 
            <title> 
              The evaluator shall perform a search of public domain sources to identify potential
              vulnerabilities in the 
              <abbr linkend="TOE" title="Target of Evaluation"> TOE </abbr>
              .
             </title>
            <note role="application"> 
              Public domain sources include the Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) dictionary for
              publicly known vulnerabilities. Public domain sources also include sites which provide free
              checking of files for viruses.
             </note> </a-element>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.3e"> 
            <title> 
              The evaluator shall conduct penetration testing, based on the identified potential
              vulnerabilities, to determine that the 
              <abbr linkend="TOE" title="Target of Evaluation"> TOE </abbr>
              is resistant to attacks performed by an attacker possessing Basic attack potential.
             </title>
            <aactivity> 
              <TSS> None. </TSS><Guidance> None. </Guidance><Tests> 
                The evaluator shall generate a report to document their findings with respect to this
                requirement. This report could physically be part of the overall test report mentioned in
                ATE_IND, or a separate document. The evaluator performs a search of public information to find
                vulnerabilities that have been found in similar applications with a particular focus on
                network protocols the application uses and document formats it parses. The evaluator shall
                also run a virus scanner with the most current virus definitions against the application files
                and verify that no files are flagged as malicious. The evaluator documents the sources
                consulted and the vulnerabilities found in the report. 
                <h:br>  </h:br>
                For each vulnerability found, the evaluator either provides a rationale with respect to its
                non-applicability, or the evaluator formulates a test (using the guidelines provided in
                ATE_IND) to confirm the vulnerability, if suitable. Suitability is determined by assessing
                the attack vector needed to take advantage of the vulnerability. If exploiting the
                vulnerability requires expert skills and an electron microscope, for instance, then a test
                would not be suitable and an appropriate justification would be formulated.
  <h:br>  </h:br>
  <h:b>For Windows, Linux, macOS and Solaris: </h:b>
The evaluator shall also run a virus scanner with the most current virus definitions against the application files and verify that no files are flagged as malicious.   </Tests> </aactivity> </a-element>
         </a-component> </change> </decision> </bunch> </technical-decisions>