<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> <bunch> <applies-to name="Protection Profile for Application Software" max-inclusive="1.3">  </applies-to><decision id="0548"> <notes> Integrity for installation tests in AppSW PP 1.3 </notes><change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fpt_tud_ext.1.3']" mode="replace"> 
          <f-element id="fpt_tud_ext.1.3"> 
            <title> 
              The application shall not download, modify, replace or update its own binary code.
             </title>
            <note role="application"> 
              This requirement applies to the code of the application; it does not apply to mobile code
              technologies that are designed for download and execution by the application.
             </note>
            <aactivity> 
              <TSS> None. </TSS><Guidance> None. </Guidance><Tests> 
                The evaluator shall verify that the application's executable files are not changed by the
                application. 
<h:p>
<depends on="selection"> <ref-id> ios </ref-id> </depends>
The evaluator shall consider the requirement met because the platform forces applications to write all data within the application working directory (sandbox).
</h:p>
For all other platforms, the evaluator shall complete the following test: 
                <testlist> 
                  <test> 
                    The evaluator shall install the application and then locate all of its executable files. The
                    evaluator shall then, for each file, save off either a hash of the file or a copy of the file
                    itself. The evaluator shall then run the application and exercise all features of the
                    application as described in the ST. The evaluator shall then compare each executable file with
                    the either the saved hash or the saved copy of the files. The evaluator shall verify that these
                    are identical.
                   </test>
                 </testlist>
               </Tests> </aactivity> </f-element> </change> </decision> </bunch> </technical-decisions>